<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cost Optimization on</title><link>https://aws-platform-team-documentation.rharshad.com/docs/cost-optimization/</link><description>Recent content in Cost Optimization on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 12:26:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aws-platform-team-documentation.rharshad.com/docs/cost-optimization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reserved Instances</title><link>https://aws-platform-team-documentation.rharshad.com/docs/cost-optimization/reserved-instances/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 12:46:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://aws-platform-team-documentation.rharshad.com/docs/cost-optimization/reserved-instances/</guid><description>The cloud is well suited for variable workloads and rapid deployment, yet many cloud-based workloads follow a more predictable pattern.
For such applications, your organization can achieve significant cost savings by using Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) Reserved Instances.
Amazon EC2 Reserved Instances enable your organization to commit to usage parameters at the time of purchase to achieve a lower hourly rate.
Reservation models are also available for Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS), Amazon ElastiCache, Amazon OpenSearch Service (OpenSearch Service), Amazon Redshift, and Amazon DynamoDB.</description></item><item><title>Savings Plan</title><link>https://aws-platform-team-documentation.rharshad.com/docs/cost-optimization/savings-plan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 12:46:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://aws-platform-team-documentation.rharshad.com/docs/cost-optimization/savings-plan/</guid><description>What is Savings Plans # Savings Plans is a flexible pricing model offering lower prices compared to On-Demand pricing, in exchange for a specific usage commitment (measured in $/hour) for a one or three-year period.
AWS offers three types of Savings Plans – Compute Savings Plans, EC2 Instance Savings Plans, and Amazon SageMaker Savings Plans.
Compute Savings Plans apply to usage across Amazon EC2, AWS Lambda, and AWS Fargate.
The EC2 Instance Savings Plans apply to EC2 usage, and Amazon SageMaker Savings Plans apply to Amazon SageMaker usage.</description></item></channel></rss>